<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Swivro</title>
    <link href="https://swivro.net/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://swivro.net" />
    <updated>2021-11-01T14:08:12-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Albert A.</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://swivro.net</id>

    <entry>
        <title>What messenger should you be using?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/what-messenger-should-you-be-using/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/what-messenger-should-you-be-using/</id>

        <updated>2021-11-01T13:06:20-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/41/telephone-586266_1920.jpg" alt="" />
                    If you are currently using an Instant Messenger like Telegram, LINE, Viber, WhatsApp, or plain SMS on your mobile device,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/41/telephone-586266_1920.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>If you are currently using an Instant Messenger like Telegram, LINE, Viber, WhatsApp, or plain SMS on your mobile device, we highly suggest picking an alternative, which is what this post is all about.</p>
<p>We only recommend instant messengers that utilize end-to-end encryption (E2EE), as E2EE encrypts all messages, voice, video, etc, before they are sent from your device to the recipient. E2EE will also protect the confidentiality and authenticity of the transmission as it passes through any part of the network. Any instant messengers we recommend below and completely free and are open source. </p>
<p><a href="https://signal.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Signal</a> is a mobile and desktop app developed by Signal Messenger LLC, which is very similar to Telegram but features full E2EE. The app provides instant messaging, as well as voice and video calling. All communications through Signal are end-to-end encrypted unless you choose to send a message as SMS. The Signal Protocol was also <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/1013.pdf">independently audited</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Signal Benefits:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Cross-platform, supporting Desktop and Mobile.</li>
<li>New features and changes can be implemented more quickly.</li>
<li>Easier to get started with and to find contacts.</li>
<li>Recommended by Elon Musk :)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Signal Downsides:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Requires a phone number</li>
<li>Poor/No documentation for 3rd party developers</li>
<li>The ownership, privacy policy, and operations of the service can change easily when a single entity controls it, potentially compromising the service later on.</li>
<li>Centralized services could be more susceptible to legislation requiring backdoor access.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="https://element.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Element</a> is the reference client for the <a href="https://matrix.org/docs/guides/introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Matrix</a> network. The <a href="https://matrix.org/docs/spec" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Matrix open standard</a> is an open-source standard for secure (<a href="https://matrix.org/blog/2016/11/21/matrixs-olm-end-to-end-encryption-security-assessment-released-and-implemented-cross-platform-on-riot-at-last" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">audit</a>), federated, real-time communication. Element/Matrix utilizes end-to-end encryption, does not require a phone number, can be used in a web browser, and is completely free, having a similar feel to the popular Discord App. Federated (aka decentralized) messengers use multiple, independent servers that are able to talk to each other (email is one example of a federated service). Federation allows system administrators to control their own server and still be a part of the larger communications network. If you're a high threat level, we suggest using Element over the Tor Network in conjunction with a VPN. We suggest to either using the Public Matrix Server on Element, or create your own for maximum privacy.</p>
<p><strong>Element Benefits:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Allows for greater control over your own data when running your own server.</li>
<li>Often allows for third party clients which can provide a more native, customized, simpler, or more accessible experience.</li>
<li>Allows you to choose who to trust your data with by choosing between multiple "public" matrix servers. We highly suggest running your own private server.</li>
<li>Generally a less juicy target for governments wanting backdoor access to everything as the trust is decentralized.</li>
<li>Server software can be verified that it matches public source code, assuming you have access to the server or you trust the person who does (ex: a family member or friend)</li>
<li>Third-party developers can contribute code and add new features, instead of waiting for a private development team to do so.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Element Downsides:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Adding new features is more complex, because these features need to be standardized and tested to ensure they work with all servers on the network.</li>
<li>Some metadata may be available (e.g., information like "who is talking to whom," but not actual message content if E2EE is used).</li>
<li>Federated servers generally require trusting your server's administrator. They may be a hobbyist or otherwise not a "security professional," and may not serve standard documents like a privacy policy or terms of service detailing how your data is utilized.</li>
<li>Server administrators sometimes choose to block other servers, which are a source of unmoderated abuse or break general rules of accepted behavior. This will hinder your ability to communicate with users on those servers.</li>
</ul>
<p>You should choose which messenger you think is a better option for you. If you're not a high threat level, and you're just looking for a more private experience when talking your friends, colleagues, or family members (whether that is via messaging, voice, or video), we suggest giving Signal a try. If you're maybe a higher threat level, want maximum anonymity, or want to share as little information as possible, we suggest going with Element/Matrix. We hope this article helped you pick a privacy-focused messenger!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why you should avoid US &amp; UK Services</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/why-you-should-avoid-us-and-uk-services/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/why-you-should-avoid-us-and-uk-services/</id>

        <updated>2021-11-01T12:13:04-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/40/computer-1591018_1920.jpg" alt="" />
                    The UKUSA Agreement is an agreement between the United Kingdom, United States, Australia, Canada, and New Zealand to cooperatively collect,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/40/computer-1591018_1920.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>The UKUSA Agreement is an agreement between the United Kingdom, United States, Australia, Canada, and New Zealand to cooperatively collect, analyze, and share intelligence. Members of this group, known as the <a href="https://www.giswatch.org/en/communications-surveillance/unmasking-five-eyes-global-surveillance-practices" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Five Eyes</a>, focus on gathering and analyzing intelligence from different parts of the world. While Five Eyes countries have agreed to <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/an-exclusive-club-the-five-countries-that-dont-spy-on-each-other" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">not spy on each other</a> as adversaries, leaks by Snowden have revealed that some Five Eyes members monitor each other's citizens and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk/2013/jun/21/gchq-cables-secret-world-communications-nsa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">share intelligence</a> to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2013/jun/10/nsa-offers-intelligence-british-counterparts-blunkett" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">avoid breaking domestic laws</a> that prohibit them from spying on their own citizens. The Five Eyes alliance also cooperates with groups of third-party countries to share intelligence (forming the Nine Eyes and Fourteen Eyes); however, Five Eyes and third-party countries can and do spy on each other.</p>
<h3>Five Eyes Countries:</h3>
<ol>
<li>Australia</li>
<li>Canada</li>
<li>New Zealand</li>
<li>United Kingdom</li>
<li>United States of America</li>
</ol>
<h4>Nine Eyes Countries:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Denmark</li>
<li>France</li>
<li>Netherlands</li>
<li>Norway</li>
</ol>
<h4>Fourteen Eyes Countries:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Belgium</li>
<li>Germany</li>
<li>Italy</li>
<li>Spain</li>
<li>Sweden</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="kdl" class="anchor">Key Disclosure Law</h2>
<p>Who is required to hand over the encryption keys to authorities? Mandatory <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Key_disclosure_law" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">key disclosure laws</a> require individuals to turn over encryption keys to law enforcement conducting a criminal investigation. How these laws are implemented (who may be legally compelled to assist) vary from nation to nation, but a warrant is generally required. Defenses against key disclosure laws include steganography and encrypting data in a way that provides plausible deniability. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steganography" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steganography</a> involves hiding sensitive information (which may be encrypted) inside of ordinary data (for example, encrypting an image file and then hiding it in an audio file). With plausible deniability, data is encrypted in a way that prevents an adversary from being able to prove that the information they are after exists (for example, one password may decrypt benign data and another password, used on the same file, could decrypt sensitive data).</p>
<h4>Key disclosure laws apply:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Antigua &amp; Barbuda</li>
<li>Australia</li>
<li>France</li>
<li>India</li>
<li>Ireland</li>
<li>Norway</li>
<li>Russia</li>
<li>South Africa</li>
<li>United Kingdom</li>
</ol>
<h4>Key disclosure laws <em>may </em>apply:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Belgium</li>
<li>Estonia</li>
<li>Finland *</li>
<li>New Zealand (unclear)</li>
<li>The Netherlands *</li>
<li>United States</li>
</ol>
<h4>Key disclosure laws don't apply:</h4>
<ol>
<li>Canada</li>
<li>Czech Republic</li>
<li>Germany</li>
<li>Iceland</li>
<li>Italy</li>
<li>Poland</li>
<li>Sweden (though it has been proposed)</li>
<li>Switzerland</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="usa" class="anchor">Why is it not recommended to choose a US-based service?</h2>
<p>Services based in the United States are not recommended because of the country's surveillance programs and use of <a href="https://www.eff.org/issues/national-security-letters/faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">National Security Letters</a> (NSLs) with accompanying gag orders, which forbid the recipient from talking about the request (EX: informing their users that they received a subpoena). This combination allows the government to <a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2013/08/more_on_the_nsa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">secretly force</a> companies to grant complete access to customer data and transform the service into a tool of mass surveillance. A perfect example of this is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lavabit#Suspension_and_gag_order" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lavabit</a> – a secure email service created by Ladar Levison. The FBI <a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/nzz888/lavabit-founder-ladar-levison-discusses-his-federal-battle-for-privacy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">requested</a> Snowden's records after finding out that he used the service. Since Lavabit did not keep logs and email content was stored encrypted, the FBI served a subpoena (with a gag order) for the service's SSL keys. Having the SSL keys would allow them to access communications (both metadata and unencrypted content) in real time for all of Lavabit's customers, not just Snowden's. Levison turned over the SSL keys and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2014/may/20/why-did-lavabit-shut-down-snowden-email" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">shut down</a> the service at the same time. The US government then <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/id/100962389" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">threatened Levison with arrest</a>, saying that shutting down the service was a violation of the court order. Avoid US services at all costs.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Choosing a VPN Provider for Privacy</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/choosing-a-vpn-provider-for-privacy/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/choosing-a-vpn-provider-for-privacy/</id>

        <updated>2021-11-01T01:16:00-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/39/New-Project-88.png" alt="" />
                    Most VPN providers simply could not care less about your privacy, log all of your data/traffic, and spy on what&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/39/New-Project-88.png" alt="" />
                <p>Most VPN providers simply could not care less about your privacy, log all of your data/traffic, and spy on what you're doing 24/7 (<em>cough cough</em> HMA VPN <em>cough cough</em>). VPN's are very useful for a number of reasons such as; hiding your IP address from websites you visit, hide your web activity from your ISP, increase your online privacy &amp; anonymity. In this article, we'll list the two best VPN's inexpensive for privacy, anonymity, security, and flexibility.</p>
<h2>Option 1: Mullvad</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://mullvad.net/">Mullvad.net</a> </strong>is a fast and inexpensive VPN starting at EUR €60/year with a serious focus on transparency and security. They have been in operation since <strong>2009</strong>. Mullvad is based in Sweden and does not have a free trial. Mullvad has <a href="https://mullvad.net/en/servers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">servers in 35 countries</a> at the time of writing this page. Picking a VPN provider with a server nearest to you will reduce latency of the network traffic you send. This is because of a shorter route (less hops) to the destination. We also think it's better for the security of the VPN provider's private keys if they use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dedicated_hosting_service" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dedicated servers</a>, instead of cheaper shared solutions (with other customers) such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_server" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">virtual private servers</a>. Mullvad's VPN clients have been independently audited by Cure53 and Assured AB in a pentest report <a href="https://cure53.de/pentest-report_mullvad_v2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">published at cure53.de</a>. The security researchers concluded:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p class="mb-0">...Cure53 and Assured AB are happy with the results of the audit and the software leaves an overall positive impression. With security dedication of the in-house team at the Mullvad VPN compound, the testers have no doubts about the project being on the right track from a security standpoint.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Mullvad also provides the source code for their desktop and mobile clients in their <a href="https://github.com/mullvad/mullvadvpn-app" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub organization</a>.  While the Mullvad VPN Client does support OpenVPN, it also supports WireGuard. WireGuard is a protocol with theoretically better security and higher reliability, and we've determined that it is indeed more reliable, and is better than OpenVPN in almost every way. This VPN also supports the <em>potential</em> future of networking <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IPv6</a>. Their network allows users to <a href="https://mullvad.net/en/blog/2014/9/15/ipv6-support/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">access services hosted on IPv6</a> as opposed to other providers who block IPv6 connections. <span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">The Mullvad VPN clients have a built-in killswitch to block internet connections outside of the VPN. They also are able to automatically start on boot. The Mullvad website is also accessible via Tor at </span><a href="https://privacy.promo/providers/vpn/o54hon2e2vj6c7m3aqqu6uyece65by3vgoxxhlqlsvkmacw6a7m7kiad.onion" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">o54hon2e2vj6c7m3aqqu6uyece65by3vgoxxhlqlsvkmacw6a7m7kiad.onion</a><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> for privacy-focused users. </span><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">I</span><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">n addition to accepting credit/debit cards and PayPal, Mullvad accepts </span><strong style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">Bitcoin</strong><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">, </span><strong style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">Bitcoin Cash</strong><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">, and </span><strong style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit;">cash/local currency</strong><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> as anonymous forms of payment. They also accept Swish and bank wire transfers. It's unfortunate that they do not accept Monero (more private than Bitcoin), however it's still good to hear that they accept some cryptocurrencies (BTC and BCH).</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Option 2: ProtonVPN</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://protonvpn.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ProtonVPN.com</a></strong> is a strong contender in the VPN space starting at $48/year, and they have been in operation since <strong>2016</strong>. ProtonVPN is based in Switzerland and offers a limited free pricing tier, as well as premium options. They offer a further 14% discount for buying a 2 year subscription. ProtonVPN has <a href="https://protonvpn.com/vpn-servers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">servers in 44 countries</a> at the time of writing this page. As mentioned, picking a VPN provider with a server nearest to you will reduce latency of the network traffic you send. This is because of a shorter route (less hops) to the destination. We also think it's better for the security of the VPN provider's private keys if they use dedicated servers, instead of cheaper shared solutions (with other customers) such as virtual private servers. As of January 2020 ProtonVPN has undergone an independent audit by SEC Consult. SEC Consult found some medium and low risk vulnerabilities in ProtonVPN's Windows, Android, and iOS applications, all of which were "properly fixed" by ProtonVPN before the reports were published. None of the issues identified would have provided an attacker remote access to a user's device or traffic. You can view individual reports for each platform at <a href="https://protonvpn.com/blog/open-source/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">protonvpn.com</a>. Like Mullvad, ProtonVPN provides the source code for their desktop and mobile clients in their <a href="https://github.com/ProtonVPN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub organization</a>. ProtonVPN does technically accept Bitcoin payments; however, you either need to have an existing account, or contact their support team in advance to register with Bitcoin. Otherwise, you cannot pay with Bitcoin or any other cryptocurrency by default. ProtonVPN does not currently support remote port forwarding, while Mullvad does. This can interfere with some applications such as P2P Torrent Clients. </p>
<p>Lastly, like Mullvad, <span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">The ProtonVPN clients have a built-in killswitch to block internet connections outside of the VPN. They also are able to automatically start on boot. ProtonVPN also offers "Tor" servers allowing you to easily connect to onion sites, but we strongly recommend using </span><a href="https://www.torproject.org/" style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">the official Tor Browser</a><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> for this purpose.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Though we have listed the two best VPN providers for privacy and anonymity above, you should carefully review our comments and determine which one would work out best for you. Both of these VPN providers are excellent, will help you take back your online privacy, and will prevent your ISP from snooping around seeing the sites you visit. If you are on an extremely tight budget, we recommend trying our 2nd recommendation above (ProtonVPN). You can even try their free plan, though we recommend using the free plan as a free trial, and if you like it, you can upgrade to get access to their Secure Core feature and dozens of more servers with a much smaller load. We hope this article helped you choose a privacy-focused VPN provider!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to mitigate DDoS Attacks</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/how-to-mitigate-ddos-attacks/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/how-to-mitigate-ddos-attacks/</id>

        <updated>2021-11-01T00:03:00-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/38/security-265130_1920.jpg" alt="" />
                    A DDoS Attack (short for distributed denial of service) is a type of cyberattack which typically targets a website. During&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/38/security-265130_1920.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>A DDoS Attack (short for distributed denial of service) is a type of cyberattack which typically targets a website. During a DDoS attack, a large amount of requests are sent to the target website, in an attempt to consume all of the server's resources (RAM, CPU, etc), therefore making the website inaccessible to the public. Below, we'll show you the most common types of DDoS Attacks, how they work, and how to mitigate them.</p>
<h2><strong>Layer 7 DDoS</strong></h2>
<p>A layer 7 DDoS is a type of DDoS attack that sends HTTP traffic to a website in order to consume resources and hamper a website's ability to deliver content to visitors. An HTTP flood attack utilizes what appear to be legitimate HTTP requests to attack a website. We will recommend three different services in order to mitigate such attacks, being DDoS-Guard, BotGuard, and Cloudflare. DDoS-Guard and Cloudflare Pro are most effective, but BotGuard will certainly mitigate medium sized attacks. Alternatively, if you wish to manually configure software on your hosting server (which is less limited compared to cloud services like Cloudflare), we recommend trying Fail2ban, Modsecurity, or Bunkerized Nginx Webserver (which includes Fail2ban and Modsecurity).</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>Layer 3/4 DDoS</strong></h2>
<p>A Layer 4 DDoS attack is often referred to as a SYN flood. A TCP connection is established in what is known as a 3-way handshake. The client sends a SYN packet to the target server, the server responds with a SYN ACK, and the client responds to that with an ACK. After the three-way handshake is complete, the TCP connection is considered established. Attackers can send SYN Floods in an attempt to stop one's network from functioning properly. Layer 3 attacks often utilize the ICMP protocol which can be stopped by disabling ICMP. Layer 4 attacks are often easy to mitigate as long as you choose the right server provider. OVH provides DDoS Protection with all of their servers and has a network capacity of over 11 TBPS.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>DDoS Attacks are extremely harmful to websites, and are of course illegal. We hope you learned something useful from this post!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Email Privacy; hide your email address</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/email-privacy-hide-your-email-address/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/email-privacy-hide-your-email-address/</id>

        <updated>2021-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/37/email-3249062_1280.png" alt="" />
                    Publicly disclosing your email address is dangerous for many reasons with the biggest reason being; by disclosing your email address,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/37/email-3249062_1280.png" alt="" />
                <p>Publicly disclosing your email address is dangerous for many reasons with the biggest reason being; by disclosing your email address, it shows what email provider you use. For example, if my Email is example@gmail.com, and I publicly disclose that email, a hacker can go to gmail.com and try to hack into my account by cracking my password or via social engineering. Your email can also end up in a bad place (ex: dangerous dark web forums), which can lead to bad things. Below, we'll be suggesting two services which allow you to create email aliases, so you can still receive emails on your email address, but your real email address won't be public.</p>
<h2><strong>Option 1: AnonAddy</strong></h2>
<div>AnonAddy lets you create your own email aliases to mask your real email address. If someone asks for your email address and you don't fully trust them, you can login to your AnonAddy account, and create a new email alias that forwards all mail sent to the email alias to your real email address. If my email alias is bob@anonaddy.me and my real email address is bobsmith@gmail.com, all mail sent to bob@anonaddy.me will be anonymously forwarded to bobsmith@gmail.com.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>TL;DR AnonAddy let's you receive emails without exposing your real email, by using email aliases. Get started for free at their website <a href="https://anonaddy.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">anonaddy.com</a></div>
<div> </div>
<h2><strong>Option 2: SimpleLogin</strong></h2>
<p>As the name suggests, SimpleLogin is very simple. SimpleLogin essentially does the same thing as AnonAddy, but as mentioned, is more simple and straight to the point. SimpleLogin is 100% open source and uses PGP Encryption (as does AnonAddy). Lastly, SimpleLogin appears to have better pricing when compared to AnonAddy, but they are both good solutions, you'll just have to choose which one you like more.<br><br>TL;DR SimpleLogin does the same thing as AnonAddy but is simpler and has better pricing. Get started for free at their website <a href="https://simplelogin.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">simplelogin.io</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The best ways to purchase cryptocurrency</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/the-best-ways-to-purchase-cryptocurrency/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/the-best-ways-to-purchase-cryptocurrency/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-31T21:54:45-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/36/cryptocurrency-6601591_1920-2.jpg" alt="" />
                    Cryptocurrency is very popular these days. Now, the question is, how do you get cryptocurrency? Well, there are a few&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/36/cryptocurrency-6601591_1920-2.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Cryptocurrency is very popular these days. Now, the question is, how do you get cryptocurrency? Well, there are a few options, and most of the popular options have a KYC (know your customer) policy, meaning you'll need to provide your ID and the last 4 digits of your Social Security Number. You can either exchange with a company (you pay with fiat currency/USD and you receive cryptocurrency), or you'll have to find someone to trade with on the internet that already has cryptocurrency, and trust that they wont scam you.</p>
<p>If you are willing to exchange with a company (you must provide your ID &amp; SSN), we highly recommend <a href="https://coinbase.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Coinbase</a>. It is very user-friendly, fast, and simple. Binance is a very similar platform, but we have some slight concerns with their friendliness towards user privacy, which is why we will not be recommending Binance. If you would like to anonymously buy and sell Bitcoin (or other cryptocurrencies), we recommend trying out Bisq; no registration required, easy to use. Bisq is open source, and utilizes the Tor Network to give their users maximum anonymity. If you already have cryptocurrency, but would like to exchange it for a different cryptocurrency (say you have Bitcoin but want to exchange to get Ethereum), we recommend having a look at <a href="https://swapzone.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Swapzone</a>. We recently used Swapzone to exchange our Litecoin for Monero, and the process was seamless. No user registration is required, simply type in what you want to exchange and the amount you want to exchange, enter your email address, and boom, you can exchange, no ID verification required. The users on Swapzone are very trustworthy, and scamming would only hurt their reputation.</p>
<p>If you're looking for a central wallet for all of your cryptocurrencies, we suggest trying out Exodus. It's completely free and private, and is very user friendly. Exodus simplifies sending and receiving cryptocurrency. Exodus also has an exchange feature where you can exchange X cryptocurrency for Y cryptocurrency, but it does have high(er) fees and limits. If you're using Coinbase, then you likely don't need Exodus, as all of your cryptocurrency is already stored in your Coinbase account.</p>
<p>Cryptocurrency is a very good thing for many reasons; including user privacy, anonymity, sending money internationally, and much more.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What web browser should you be using?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/what-web-browser-should-you-be-using/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/what-web-browser-should-you-be-using/</id>

        <updated>2021-11-01T13:21:40-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/35/New-Project-84.png" alt="" />
                    It's time to ditch Google Chrome, Opera, and Vivaldi. In this post, we're going to suggest some browsers that are&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/35/New-Project-84.png" alt="" />
                <p>It's time to ditch Google Chrome, Opera, and Vivaldi. In this post, we're going to suggest some browsers that are great for privacy, anonymity, and security.</p>
<h2><strong>1.</strong> <strong>Firefox</strong></h2>
<p>Firefox is fast, reliable, open-source, and is focused on user privacy. With the new modernized UI along with DNS over HTTPS, you just have to try Firefox! If you're a Chrome user and want some privacy, we think you'll like the feel of Firefox. Don't forget to adjust the settings according to our recommendations:</p>
<h4>Disabling WebRTC in Firefox</h4>
<p>TL;DR Set "media.peerconnection.enabled" to "false" in "about:config".</p>
<p><strong>Explained:</strong></p>
<ol class="long-string-list">
<li>Enter "about:config" in the firefox address bar and press enter.</li>
<li>Press the button "I'll be careful, I promise!"</li>
<li>Search for "media.peerconnection.enabled"</li>
<li>Double click the entry, the column "Value" should now be "false"</li>
<li>Done. Do the <a href="https://ipleak.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WebRTC leak test</a>.</li>
</ol>
<p>If you want to make sure every single WebRTC-related setting is really disabled change these settings:</p>
<ol class="long-string-list">
<li>media.peerconnection.turn.disable = true</li>
<li>media.peerconnection.use_document_iceservers = false</li>
<li>media.peerconnection.video.enabled = false</li>
<li>media.peerconnection.identity.timeout = 1</li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>2. Tor Browser</strong></h2>
<p class="card-text">Tor Browser is a great choice if you need an extra layer of anonymity &amp; security. It's a modified version (fork) of Firefox, which comes with pre-installed privacy add-ons, encryption, and multiple proxy layers. The Tor Network is a network of virtual tunnels that allows you to improve your privacy and security on the Internet. Tor works by sending your web traffic through three random servers (also known as Tor relays) in the Tor network. The last relay in the circuit (the “exit relay” or "exit node") then sends the traffic out onto the public internet. You can access websites via the Tor Network by downloading the Tor Browser. Your ISP will only be able to see that you are hitting a Tor Node, and nothing else. A VPN in conjunction with Tor is recommended; we recommend trying ProtonVPN or Mullvad. You're welcome to use Tor without a VPN, but then you risk the government/your ISP blocking you from accessing all safe Tor Exit Nodes, forcing you to use the government's exit node so they can inspect your traffic.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>3. Bromite</strong></h2>
<p class="card-text">Bromite is a Chromium-based browser (for Android Devices) with privacy and security enhancements, built-in adblocking and DNS over HTTPS support; it includes patches from the open source ungoogled-chromium project and other privacy-focused open source projects. If you like Google Chrome on Android, but want some more privacy, you will without a doubt love Bromite.</p>
<p>We hope this quick article helped you choose a new privacy-focused web browser, so you can take your online privacy back. Have a nice day!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Staying Anonymous Online</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/staying-anonymous-online/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/staying-anonymous-online/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-31T22:44:31-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/34/hacker-3342696_1920.jpg" alt="" />
                    Whether you like it or not, your ISP is very likely spying on your every move on the internet. Most&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/34/hacker-3342696_1920.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Whether you like it or not, your ISP is very likely spying on your every move on the internet. Most notably; Comcast, AT&amp;T, T-Mobile, and Verizon. We're going to help you stay anonymous and private, so your ISP won't be able to spy on you for any longer.</p>
<p><strong>Option 1: </strong>Use the Tor Browser</p>
<div class="card col-12">
<div class="card-wrapper">
<div class="bottom-line">
<p class="mbr-text mbr-fonts-style display-7">Tor is a network of virtual tunnels that allows you to improve your privacy and security on the Internet. Tor works by sending your web traffic through three random servers (also known as Tor relays) in the Tor network. The last relay in the circuit (the “exit relay” or "exit node") then sends the traffic out onto the public internet. You can access websites via the Tor Network by downloading the Tor Browser. Your ISP will only be able to see that you hitting a Tor Node, and nothing else. A VPN in conjunction with Tor is recommended; we recommend trying ProtonVPN or Mullvad. If you use Tor without a VPN, your ISP will see that you're hitting a Tor Node. This can give them clues to something or can flag you as high risk.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="card col-12">
<div class="card-wrapper">
<div class="top-line row">
<div class="col"> </div>
<div> </div>
<div><strong>Option 2: </strong>Use a standalone VPN</div>
<div>
<div class="card col-12">
<div class="card-wrapper">
<div class="bottom-line">
<p class="mbr-text mbr-fonts-style display-7">If you do not want to use the Tor Browser, which relays your web traffic through multiple different servers (making you anonymous) which can slow down a website's load-time a bit, you may use a standalone VPN without Tor. Using a VPN with Tor most definitely makes you more anonymous, but if your goal is to only stop your ISP from seeing what you're doing, and to hide your home IP address from websites, a standalone VPN is indeed a good idea. We recommend trying <a href="https://protonvpn.com/" class="text-primary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ProtonVPN</a> or <a href="https://mullvad.net/" class="text-primary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mullvad</a>. Please ensure that your DNS resolvers on your device are not set to your ISP's DNS resolvers. If they are, change them to AdGuard DNS, BlahDNS, or Quad9 DNS.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="card col-12">
<div class="card-wrapper">
<div class="top-line row">
<div class="col"> </div>
<div> </div>
<div><strong>Option 3: </strong>Route all internet traffic through Tor</div>
<div>
<section id="features10-1l" class="features9 cid-sMDCqoOUkP">
<div class="container">
<div class="row mt-4">
<div class="card col-12">
<div class="card-wrapper">
<div class="bottom-line">
<p class="mbr-text mbr-fonts-style display-7">If you're a high threat level that is in need of all internet traffic to be routed through the Tor Network, we recommend using Tails OS. This OS is a Linux Distro, based off of Debian. It routes all traffic through the Tor Network, and blocks all traffic that does not go through Tor (both in/out). As you may have guessed, Tails OS is focused on privacy and anonymity. If you are using Microsoft Windows, and for some reason cannot switch to Linux, you can either try <a href="https://www.torifier.com/index.html" class="text-primary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Torrifier</a> or <a href="https://github.com/basil00/TorWall/releases" class="text-primary" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tallow</a> (which both route all traffic through Tor), or you can create a Virtual Machine on your machine via VirtualBox, install Tails OS on it, and use that VM for accessing the internet.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Njalla, a privacy-first hosting company.</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/njalla-a-privacy-first-hosting-company/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/njalla-a-privacy-first-hosting-company/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-31T16:20:24-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/33/Screenshot_64.png" alt="" />
                    njalla was founded in the year 2017. njalla is privacy-friendly and free-speech. As njalla says, "When you buy a domain&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/33/Screenshot_64.png" alt="" />
                <div class="card col-12">
<div class="card-wrapper">
<div class="bottom-line">
<p class="mbr-text mbr-fonts-style display-7">njalla was founded in the year 2017. njalla is privacy-friendly and free-speech. As njalla says, "When you buy a domain in our system, we're actually purchasing it for ourselves. We will be the actual owners of the domain, however, you will still have the full control over the domain name. You can either use our information, our nameservers or you can go with your own. If you ever want to move the domain from our system, we'll of course give you the domain without any additional costs". Their goal is to minimize your visibility (personal details) to the public. As for VPS/Server Hosting, they provide secure servers at a low cost. njalla also accepts cryptocurrency for increased anonymity.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Hydrogen Aerospace&#x27;s Bad Security</title>
        <author>
            <name>Albert A.</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://swivro.net/hydrogen-aerospaces-bad-security/"/>
        <id>https://swivro.net/hydrogen-aerospaces-bad-security/</id>

        <updated>2021-11-01T14:08:12-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/32/Screenshot_63.png" alt="" />
                    Hydrogen Aerospace is a startup France-based aerospace company. We truly like their vision, but when it comes to cybersecurity, they&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://swivro.net/media/posts/32/Screenshot_63.png" alt="" />
                <p>Hydrogen Aerospace is a startup France-based aerospace company. We truly like their vision, but when it comes to cybersecurity, they quite literally aren't the one. We contacted Hydrogen on October 24th, 2021, regarding critical security issues on their website. It has taken them over 24 hours to fix one of many security issues, and we have yet to receive any formal response via email. The one simple issue they have fixed involved simply modifying a file on their server that hosts their website, which, as mentioned, took them over a ridiculous 24 hours. After we sent Hydrogen an encrypted email (with the list of security issues), we heard from them on Twitter, saying "They saw your email and will take corrective actions even if a lot of what you mentioned is already done". That last part is stupidly incorrect, as we proved that the security issues were still present. They then replied to our reply on Twitter (where we asked if we can expect a response), and the reply said "The team saw your email, but will not give you update about it for security reason". This is obvious straight bullsh*t. There should be no reason as to why we cannot receive a formal response from the company stating that they received my email, they understand the severity of these security issues, they are working on fixing them, and they appreciate our report &amp; good intentions. Essentially ignoring our email (we are to assume it has been ignored or is not taken seriously seeing that we have not received a response) with a list of critical security issues that need to be solved is extremely rude and unprofessional. If they really can't give us an update via email due to "security issue", then this indicates they have another security issue affecting their email system. Hydrogen Aerospace needs to do better, act more professional, and learn to communicate properly when it comes to critical security issues that need to be solved; because so far we have only heard back from them via an unsecure privacy-violating social media platform (Twitter) where we were provided with a vague and irrational response.<br><br><strong>October 29th, 2021 Update: </strong>It's been over 6 days now and a security flaw that we reported has still yet to be fixed, and can be fixed in literally less than 5 minutes. We had to respond to the Owner (of hydrogen-aero.com) on Twitter over 5 times aggressively asking for a simple formal response (to our email) stating that they received it and that they are working on fixing the issues. All we got is a pointless delayed response saying "Thank you". Please, for your own online safety, stay away from this website with poor security.<br><br><strong>October 31st, 2021 Update: </strong>It's stupidly ridiculous how this company can't fix a very simple yet dangerous security issue. We don't promote hacking, but go ahead and exploit this issue that they refuse to fix. They are missing a DMARC record on their domain hydrogen-aero.com, so go ahead and send a forged email to whoever you want originating from <em>hi@hydrogen-aero.com</em> containing a (fake) virus link. Their website is also <strong>extremely</strong> vulnerable to the most simple DDoS attacks (HTTP Flood Attacks). OVH provides transport-level DDoS Protection, but not application-level, we're not sure if they know this or not because their website has no web application firewall (we were able to access the website via various types of bots including fake search engine bots). Hopefully this will force them to fix this issue.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
