<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Swivro News</title>
    <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Swivro News</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2015-2021, Swivro.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:45:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//swivro.net/news/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>August 14th Website Changes</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/august-14-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:45:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/august-14-changes/</guid>
      <description>I made some changes today to the home website (swivro.net). The HOME page features newly updated images of Swivro Products, including Levin, and the new File7. I also added some symbols to the buttons, as the donate button has a $ symbol on it, and the &amp;ldquo;View all Services&amp;rdquo; button has a magic wand symbol on it. Looks neat.
There is also now an endorsements page, displaying organizations, projects, and services that are not owned by Swivro, but ones that Swivro endorses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File7</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/file7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 19:48:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/file7/</guid>
      <description>Introducing File7, a free file storage platform, a great privacy-focused Google Drive alternative. It has pretty much just as many features as Google Drive does, including file sharing (via link), document editing, file creation, virus protection, and more. It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely free and includes no unethical tracking or ads. Learn more about File7 on our Services &amp;amp; Brands Page accessible via https://swivro.net/services or via Tor at o66mxachpue5u4hv7gnuq2efovklbcowwh47wypm73eu4imlvmeuybyd.onion/services.html
You get 5GB of disk space for free on File7, which is better than having 15GB for free at Google Drive with all of their nasty file scanners, trackers, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#39;s Privacy Invasion</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/apple-privacy-invasion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 17:36:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/apple-privacy-invasion/</guid>
      <description>On August 5th, 2021, Apple Inc. announced new technological measures meant to apply across virtually all of its devices under the umbrella of “Expanded Protections for Children”. While child exploitation is a serious problem, and while efforts to combat it are almost unquestionably well-intentioned, Apple&amp;rsquo;s proposal introduces a backdoor that threatens to undermine fundamental privacy protections for all users of Apple products. Apple&amp;rsquo;s proposed technology works by continuously monitoring photos saved or shared on the user&amp;rsquo;s iPhone, iPad, or Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing the Elephant</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/elephant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:08:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/elephant/</guid>
      <description>Our logo is now an Elephant (thanks to Flaticon). Why an Elephant? Elephant&amp;rsquo;s are cool animals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Hosting DraugerOS&#39;s New York Download Server!</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/ny-draugeros-download-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 22:27:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/ny-draugeros-download-mirror/</guid>
      <description>DraugerOS is a linux gaming OS, in fact, in our opinion, it is the best linux gaming OS. Learn more about DraugerOS at their website, accessible via DraugerOS.org. Moving on.. We&amp;rsquo;re now happily hosting a mirror of the DraugerOS Download Repository, accessible at draugeros-ny1.swivro.net/download.draugeros.org in your web browser. This will be (at least one of) DraugerOS&amp;rsquo;s New York Download Servers. This will, hopefully, drastically improve download speeds for DraugerOS users based in or near NYC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Theme Transition</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/dark-theme-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:15:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/dark-theme-transition/</guid>
      <description>As most (all) of our services &amp;amp; brands use a light (bright/white) theme by default, we will soon begin transitioning all of them to a dark theme, so your corneas no longer burn. We will also do this to match the Swivro website, as we have changed the Swivro website to be dark themed (if you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, it was previously light themed). Dark theme is the better theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is LTS?</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/what-is-lts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 16:43:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/what-is-lts/</guid>
      <description>You may notice that on some of our brands, products, or services (on our Brands &amp;amp; Services page), have (LTS) marked next to them. LTS simply stands for Long Term Support. Brands/Services on our Brands &amp;amp; Services page which are marked as LTS mean they do not plan to be abandoned (without notice), are very stable &amp;amp; are production ready, and are good enough quality to have Long Term Support (LTS) by Swivro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bytefend&#39;s unacceptable behaviour</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/bytefends-unacceptable-behaviour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 13:01:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/bytefends-unacceptable-behaviour/</guid>
      <description>Around 2 weeks ago, one of our brands/services which we currently do not publicly associate ourselves with, was experiencing major downtime due to a Protocol offensive (transport level) DDoS Attack, aka a Layer 4 DDoS Attack. We were seeking a DDoS Protection Service. We didn&amp;rsquo;t go with CloudFlare initially, so we were seeking alternatives. Our #1 option was Shovl.io but they are currently closed for new signups, so we later found Bytefend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Nova Search</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/nova-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 16:11:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/nova-search/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re introducing Nova Search, an upcoming service managed by Swivro. Nova Search is a fast privacy-respecting online search engine. Nova Search is a completely anonymous search engine, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t track you and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sell your data. It is scheduled to be released at the end of this monthy, being July, or early August. The code for Nova Search is ready but we are seeking a hosting provider for Nova Search, and right now our #1 option is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Azure Platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>//swivro.net/news/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 15:19:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swivro.net/news/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello world! This is first TEST post on Swivro News!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
